<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: random | the blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T00:08:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[omnomn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ode To Chocolate Covered Gummy Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/07/31/chocolate-covered-gummy-bears/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-31T20:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/07/31/chocolate-covered-gummy-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can't remember when I was first introduced to these delectable little guys. It was love at first bite. Seriously. I could eat a whole bagful whilst programming furiously away. Tonight I decided to scour the internet to find where I could procure chocolate covered gummy bears... in bulk.</p>

<p>After searching high and low for about 30 minutes or so, I finally found what I decided was the <a href="http://www.nutsinbulk.com/milk-chocolate-gummy-bears-5-pounds.html?productid=milk-chocolate-gummy-bears-5-pounds&channelid=NEXTA&utm_source=CSEs&utm_medium=Nextag&utm_campaign=CSE">best price to least sketchiest vendor ratio</a>. I had to refrain from selecting the option for 25 pounds of chocolate covered gummy bears for $148.75. As I began checking out, I noticed a little countdown timer pop up in the lower right corner of the screen letting me know that if I checked out within the next five minutes, I would save an extra 5%. What a good idea for countering shopping cart abandonment, I thought.  Not that I would abandon my chocolate covered gummy bears.</p>

<p>One reviewer warned of high shipping charges. Hmm... perhaps I ought to buy more in that case, I thought. So you know those times you get stuck on the internet? Well, I'm having one of those moments right now. It became painfully obvious to me I wasn't going to be making it out of here within the next five minutes.  I mean, here I am just innocently trying to buy a shitload ton of chocolate covered gummy bears, and I am waiting patiently for the shipping rates to appear so I can make an informed decision as to whether I ought to get the five pound package or the ten.  I almost gave up thinking the site was stuck. Finally, after 5 minutes of watching the brown spinner go round and round the charges showed up. FedEx was going to be $13 for 10 pounds and ... (hrm, another 5 minutes, perhaps I ought to go take a shower while I wait). Ok, out of the shower and still waiting. I gave up and called it a night, and decided I would call them in the morning.</p>

<p>Three thoughts were running though my mind at this point: 1) seriously, how hard can it be to buy chocolate covered gummy bears?  2) perhaps I ought to wait until closer to Christmas to justify a larger purchase, and 3) if anyone within driving distance from the middle of SF wants in, <a href="joann.kuo@gmail.com">let me know</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
