<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-01T09:52:23-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[omnomn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design From The Inside Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/12/01/design-from-the-inside-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T09:34:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/12/01/design-from-the-inside-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was the first time I&#8217;d mentioned it. I preferred to start simple and then add complexity as needed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holiday Tree]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/30/holiday-tree/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T11:01:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/30/holiday-tree</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Executive decisions have to be made.  It was becoming increasingly apparent to me that unless I put Christmas tree into the weekly sprint it would never get done.</p>

<p>Attempt #1: Kyle and Andrew went with me to get it but the place we wanted to get it from didn&#8217;t have stands. And to get a stand would exceed our allocated bandwidth. So we went back empty-handed.</p>

<p>Attempt #2: Ronald and Keri and I went to Target to get a stand. We found ourselves staring at an empty shelf. They were out of stands. Foiled yet again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leveling Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/30/leveling-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T10:59:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/30/leveling-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>General mktg (D)
Prod mktg (D,J)
PR tricks (J)
Product design (J, SM)
Engg build (J,B,K)
Data (K, SR)</p>

<p>Light fire under ass
How can we do better
Mood is +</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doing The Startup Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_doing-the-startup-thing/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T20:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_doing-the-startup-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>San Francisco is a sort of a microcosm in that people from all over the world flock here to &#8220;do the startup thing&#8221;.  Since moving here, I&#8217;ve met so many people who&#8217;ve traveled far and wide from Europe, Australia, the Midwest, China and more. Why? This is the place where magic happens. Perhaps if you come here, some of the magic will rub off on you too. It sort of reminds me of the time I was in Dubai, where there was no such thing as a shortage of land. They simply created it. Here in the Valley, there&#8217;s no shortage of ideas. You simply come up with more.  There&#8217;s no shame in trying and failing.</p>

<p>The real shame is in not trying at all.</p>

<p>This is what the New Web is all about. Less about what technology can do than what we can do using technology.  When you take a careful look, you realize that it&#8217;s not the idea that&#8217;s the important thing.  The idea is secondary.  The primary goal here is to simply making something happen.  Anything.</p>

<p>As long as we prove something of ourselves.</p>

<p>My college roommate gave me a framed quote from Johann Wolfgang von Goethe which stated “Whatever you can do, or dream you can do, begin it. Boldness has genius, power, and magic in it. Begin it now.”</p>

<p>What the German novelist, dramatist, poet, humanist, scientist, and philosopher was the fundamental fuel of startups. The spirit of the times ignites within each and every one of us the urge to make some sort of impact upon the world. We live in a modern-day renaissance inciting passion and fervor and sense of urgency which is the most exciting thing about being alive.</p>

<p>Here and now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup Is Fashion]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/10/19/P_startup-as-fashion/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T18:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/10/19/P_startup-as-fashion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Los Angeles you hear people talking about blue jeans and sporting the latest fashionable large handbags and sunglasses.  Replace the celebrity gossip with excited exchanges on the latest idea, shiny new experiences, and plans to gain traction. San Francisco is quite similar to LA in the sense that both places have a fashion undercurrents in the air. You can&#8217;t see it, but you can definitely feel something amiss.</p>

<p>A few properties characterize the most successful startups as I&#8217;ve observed and experienced from the trenches.  Here they are, in no particular order:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Gone: Heavy spec writing.<br>
Instead: Lightweight specs and standups.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The unknown corporation.<br>
Instead: The personable touch.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Ignoring the customer.<br>
Instead: The customer is king.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Poor user experiences.<br>
Instead: Spotlight on the user experience. Whimsy, personality, fun. Character. This is why copyrighting is so important these days.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Just build it. <br>
Instead: Figure out what you will build and market and sell it first. Then build it.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Silos of demarcation.<br>
Instead: Integrated, small design-build teams who can turn on a dime.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Boring jobs.<br>
Instead: You can have your cake and eat it too.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The corporate zombie.<br>
Instead: The enlightened, self-motivated employee.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Playing by the rules.<br>
Intead: Making the rules. Or in some cases, breaking them first.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Believing you can&#8217;t.<br>
Instead: Believing you can.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional models and institutions.<br>
Instead: Forging your own way.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional glass ceilings.<br>
Instead: Fuck you money.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>These characteristics comprise the <a href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_doing-the-startup-thing/">New Renaissance</a> and if you&#8217;ve ever been in the trenches yourself, then you&#8217;ll know what I&#8217;m talking about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
