<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-28T22:32:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[omnomn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[If Your App Was Human]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/if-your-app-was-human/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T19:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/if-your-app-was-human</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Javascript(?) giving your app personality.</p>

<p>First it was about features. Feature war
Now it&#8217;s about removing features
Forget about inventing new experiences. What about cleaning up the existing ones we have to suffer though in our daily lives?</p>

<p>Omnomn helping app. Just built a prototype and the hyperlink made the feeling rather snappy. It was a bit harsh. I wanted to make it smooth and sexy. Or perhaps bouncy and a bit playful.  This is the genius of the likes of Steve Jobs and Walt Disney.  I felt like I was standing on the shoulders of great men.</p>

<p>I was ready to build.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Format For Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/new-format-for-plan/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T16:46:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/new-format-for-plan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>App Connections page should look like: https://www.easel.io/documents/e3801d92405f7955#e3801d92405f7955
Finished Campaign analytics should look like:
https://www.easel.io/documents/88b0ddec331fb7c1?#88b0ddec331fb7c1</p>

<p>Issue #1: AM is confused when different stats appear in admin blast data vs. in app
Issue #2: Customers may be confused by numbers that are displayed w/o an explanation as to what they mean (eg. 2 customer counts).
Issue #3: Customers want to see campaign result detail (I thought I had this many customers, why does it say only this many got reached?)
Issue #4: Terminology is all over the place.  Eg. it&#8217;s &#8220;Runs from&#8221; and &#8220;runs to&#8221; in one place but &#8220;Start&#8221; and &#8220;end&#8221; in another.
Issue #5: Still outstanding is to decide how to treat single email/multiple entries.
Issue #6: FB fan inclusion into stats
Issue #7: Terms need to be defined.</p>

<p>Resolution #1: AM should seldom have to go into admin.
Resolution #2: We make it clear which numbers mean what and add tooltips where necessary
Resolution #3: Reach is defined as FB+emails+text+bounce
Resolution #4: Lets go w/ Start and end when referring to campaigns.
Resolution #5: Waiting on Sailesh.
Resolution #6: Include Fb fans into stats
Resolution #7: I defined some terms.</p>

<p>Quick fix changes:</p>

<ol>
<li>In admin, replace the words &#8220;Aggregate Information&#8221; with &#8220;Stats&#8221; and change that data in admin to reflect same exact data as what is shown to customers
Emails: 6089.0; Opens: 940.0; Visits: 285.0; Optouts: 23.0; Bounces: 4.0</li>
<li>In admin, make &#8220;Experiment&#8221; the same size as the other 2 headers.</li>
<li>In admin, hide Experiments if we are not actively using.</li>
<li>In admin, replace the words &#8220;Blast Groups&#8221; with &#8220;Sent to Mailgun&#8221;</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make Rules]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/make-rules/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T15:28:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/make-rules</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Templates.</li>
<li>New campaign template</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start From The Inside Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/start-from-the-inside-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T13:50:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/28/start-from-the-inside-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Strugling w/ the stats</p>

<p>Do not do this: start designing the dash
do this instead: design lower pages, maybe even sections of a lower page</p>

<p>Stats will globally affect what&#8217;s shown on the dash. Improve the individual pages then you can rearrange after they are done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doing The Startup Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_doing-the-startup-thing/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T20:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_doing-the-startup-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Mom,</p>

<p>San Francico is a sort of a microcosm in that people from all over the world flock here to &#8220;do the startup thing&#8221;.  Since moving here, I&#8217;ve met so many people who&#8217;ve traveled far and wide from Europe, Australia, the Midwest, China and more. Why? This is the place where magic happens. Perhaps if you come here, some of the magic will rub off on you too. It sort of reminds me of being in Dubai, where there was no such thing as a shortage of land. They simply created it. Here in the Valley, there&#8217;s no shortage of ideas. You simply come up with more.  There&#8217;s no shame in trying and failing.</p>

<p>The real shame is in not trying at all.</p>

<p>This is what the New Web is all about. Less about what technology can do than what we can do using technology.  When you take a careful look, you realize that it&#8217;s not the idea that&#8217;s the important thing.  The idea is secondary.  The primary goal here is to simply making something happen.  Anything.</p>

<p>As long as we prove something of ourselves.</p>

<p>Johann Wolfgang von Goethe was a German novelist, dramatist, poet, humanist, scientist, philosopher, and for ten years chief minister of state at Weimar in the late 18th and early 19th centuries.  He stated most eloquently about the human spirit we witness today:</p>

<p>“Until one is committed, there is hesitancy, the chance to draw back. Concerning all acts of initiative (and creation), there is one elementary truth, the ignorance of which kills countless ideas and splendid plans: that the moment one definitely commits oneself, then Providence moves too.</p>

<p>All sorts of things occur to help one that would never otherwise have occurred. A whole stream of events issues from the decision, raising in one&#8217;s favor all manner of unforeseen incidents and meetings and material assistance, which no man could have dreamed would have come his way. Whatever you can do, or dream you can do, begin it.</p>

<p>Boldness has genius, power, and magic in it. Begin it now.”</p>

<p>What Goethe was describing was what we are witnessing today with startups. The spirit of the times ignites within each and every one of us the urge to make some sort of impact upon the world. We live in a modern-day renaissance inciting passion and fervor and sense of urgency which is the most exciting thing about being alive and here.  Now.</p>

<p>I know it&#8217;s hard for you to understand what I&#8217;m talking about since it seems sort of like a utopian state of work. Far removed from the traditional view of work.  The other day I came up with <a href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_startup-as-fashion/">a dozen characteristics</a> which characterize the best of them in my humble observations from the trenches.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Not Getting Married]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/im-not-getting-married/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T19:29:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/im-not-getting-married</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's All One Big Giant Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/its-all-one-big-giant-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T19:27:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/its-all-one-big-giant-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's A Branding Exercise]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/its-a-branding-exercise/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T19:27:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/its-a-branding-exercise</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup Is Fashion]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_startup-as-fashion/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T18:54:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_startup-as-fashion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Mom,</p>

<p>You know how in LA you would hear people talking about blue jeans and sporting the latest fashionable large handbags and sunglasses? Well, instead here you hear about the latest idea, what the experience will be like, and plans to gain traction. There is definitely a fashion undercurrent in the air here as far as being &#8220;startuppy&#8221; goes.I was thinking about this the other day and I quickly identified a dozen in order to give you an idea of what it looks like, as it may be difficult for you to comprehend without actually being here.</p>

<p>Here they are in no particular order:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Gone: Heavy spec writing.<br>
Instead: Lightweight, standups instead.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The unknown corporation.<br>
Instead: The personable touch.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Ignoring the customer<br>
Instead: The customer is king.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Poor user experiences<br>
Instead: Spotlight on the user experience. Whimsy, personality, fun. Character. This is why copyrighting is so important these days.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Just build it <br>
Instead: Figure out what you will build and market and sell it first. Then build it</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Silos of demarcatation<br>
Instead: Integrated, small design-build teams who can turn on a dime.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Boring jobs<br>
Instead: You can have your cake and eat it too</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The corporate zombie<br>
Instead: The enlightened, self-motivated employee</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Playing by the rules<br>
Intead: Making the rules. Or in some cases, breaking them first</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Believing you can&#8217;t.<br>
Instead: Believing you can.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional models and institutions<br>
Instead: Forging your own way</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional glass ceilings<br>
Instead: Fuck you money</p></li>
</ol>


<p>It seems these characteristics can be found in organizations large or small, and there&#8217;s no reason why one cannot implement one or a few today regardless of what they do for work or what position they are in.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
