<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T00:08:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[omnomn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have a Point of View]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/20/have-a-point-of-view/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T19:40:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/20/have-a-point-of-view</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The best products have a point of view. The strongest brands do. <advertising></p>

<p>I was frustrated at our lack of willingness to be decisive about big decisions. Nothing is irreversible. And why we were treating it as such was beyond me.</p>

<p>Every product, every startup, ought to have a strong POV. My POV for omnomn was that people should help other people more, and that people ought to ask for help more. The hypothesis was that there simply was no mechanism by which people could easily see what others needed. And if you don&#8217;t know what the person sitting across from you needed, how could you help them?</p>

<p>The shape of behavior is changing, and the internet was largely fueling this phenomenon. Not that this happens overnight. You can think of it like erosion. If you look at the rocks on the coast of XXX what you see is marvelous formations with sensuous and curvaceous shapes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Finding Your Limits]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/20/on-finding-your-limits/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T19:27:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/20/on-finding-your-limits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Redlining. Pushing your limits. Some people climb Mt. Everest. I work at a startup.</p>

<p>Thanks to S for being a slavedriver. If you survive, you&#8217;ll come out stronger in the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Designing And Building]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/15/on-designing-and-building/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T23:18:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/15/on-designing-and-building</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were born to create.</p>

<p>Environment matters.</p>

<p>Inspired by a thread I posted to on LinkedIn just a few days ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Should Boys Have All The Fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/15/why-should-boys-have-all-the-fun/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T21:32:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/15/why-should-boys-have-all-the-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Month 14]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/month-14/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T21:30:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/month-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over drinks one night, I asked my friend what he&#8217;d learned from his startup.</p>

<p>I think back and I have gained so much experience from the past 14 months I wouldn&#8217;t trade it for the world. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it was pretty rough. I&#8217;m not a natural hustler, and I was definitely no coder.</p>

<p>The top 10 things I learned were:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Know why you&#8217;re doing what you&#8217;re doing. I sort of fell into local online advertising. It wasn&#8217;t a natural passion of mine admittedly, but I was there to learn come hell or high water. All I knew was that I wanted the startup experience, and that was exactly what I&#8217;d got.</p></li>
<li><p>When you love what you do you don&#8217;t do it for the money. This is the #1 reason companies today are having a tough time finding development talent. Why the hell would you help raise someone else&#8217;s baby when you could have your own?</p></li>
<li><p>Always be learning. The day you stop learning is probably the day you should leave.</p></li>
<li><p>Ruthlessly prioritize.</p></li>
<li><p>Most of all, you will change yourself.</p></li>
<li><p>Forget having hobbies.</p></li>
<li><p>Your role shifts from being consumer to creator.</p></li>
<li><p>Always be shipping.</p></li>
<li><p>Question everything.</p></li>
<li><p>Have no fear.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creator]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/creator/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T21:04:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/creator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Obj: To make the point that
1) There&#8217;s never been a greater time in history of mankind for the individual to achieve (history lesson)
2) Builders rule the world (the one w/ the code makes the rules)
3) How to start? (flexible, learn to surf, get the right tools)</p>

<p>Join a startup. Even if it fails, you have to remember #1 goal is to learn. If you are learning from the experience day in and day out, nothing is a loss. A startup is really about the journey (and to a lesser extent I would argue, the destination). One of the things I brought to my startup at the beginning was a naivete mind. Looking back, this was sort of a double-edged sword. Since I wasn&#8217;t encumbered by the &#8220;knowing way it should work&#8221;, this made me take a lot more of a beating than I probably should have had in working with small business owners. But it allowed me to learn on my own difficult lessons which are ingrained in my mind more deeply than it otherwise would be had I learned by hearing others&#8217; experiences. There is no substitute for being in the trenches.</p>

<p>Somehow, we made it to Series A.</p>

<p>I learned a lot of things this first year. For example, that I needed to have the ability to process information much faster. I was thrown in the deep end of the pool, drowning in a pool of emails.  I learned to set up filters. Before, I would deliberate on things for what seems now like ages. You might say I acquired an affinity for speed. I also learned to use the internet as a research tool. I learned to spy on competitors products. I learned to communicate better. I learned to organize my thoughts better. I learned that the sky&#8217;s the limit and that you wake up each morning asking, what should we build today? And then making it happen.</p>

<p>I learned to build a team.</p>

<p>Somewhere along the way, I came across a nascent product that promised to help me build better. It was called Easel, started by two young idealistic guys and funded by Y-Combinator.  It was an ambitious start to a project that promised to revolutionize the way web products were built. After I created my first few pages, I was hooked. My development team loved it. I was building in the browser, real time, and one could literally watch as the page got built. Hot damn. It was like magic. I can&#8217;t tell how I felt that I was watching man land on the moon when I used the bookmarklet to import the entire Basecamp calendar into my document. (It was for a concept, and I ended up creating my own just for the record).</p>

<p>I was like Mozart composing his Requiem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Immersion]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/full-immersion/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T21:03:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/full-immersion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Kill The Unicorn]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/dont-kill-the-unicorn/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T20:55:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/14/dont-kill-the-unicorn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have no conception of how things should be built. All I knew is I wasn&#8217;t slow, things were getting done, and the team loved it. I felt pressured every day, and I knew we were redlining. It&#8217;s almost like seeing how fast your racecar can go.</p>

<p>Needless to say, I would have like to have a bit more breathing room. But is it possible to iterate and to come up with good ideas, faster? Is there a bound to this forced compression of creativity?  I didn&#8217;t like it, but I was game to push the envelope. I had signed up for this. Completely and voluntarily.</p>

<p>The unicorn was chained up because someone found that its horn had magical powers. But slowly, day by day without freedom to play and to roam, its powers gradually began to wane.</p>

<p>Don&#8217;t kill the unicorn.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[There Is No Such Thing As A Unicorn]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/12/there-is-no-such-thing-as-a-unicorn/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T18:28:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/12/there-is-no-such-thing-as-a-unicorn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>6:30 and it&#8217;s pitch dark outside. I was deep in thought about the dilemma of the unicorn.  There is no such thing.</p>

<p>Just this morning I gave a sneak peek of the mobile user experience to the team.</p>

<p>The best designs take in all the external inputs at the beginning. This can come in all forms including email, passing conversation, at the watercooler, one-on-ones, surfing the internet late at night. You&#8217;re like a sponge absorbing as much information as possible. Once you&#8217;ve gathered enough informtion, it&#8217;s time to start synthesizing and digesting it. You can think of this as a delectable reduction you&#8217;re making to draw out all the intense flavors of the ingredients added or a stew which gets better with time or wine which ferments, cheese which ages.</p>

<p>Good ideas cannot be forced but tend to come once initial inputs have taken place.</p>

<p>The best part about reducing the time to build? Where speed to market is critical, being able to design-build-test-iterate quickly becomes paramount.  And the best environments allow you to play, then take the results of the play and build something with it that is useful. This is sustainable design. No, sustainable creation.</p>

<p>Unicorn def: Those who believe that fast design-build will rule the world.</p>

<p>http://www.marketingexperiments.com/improving-website-conversion/powerful-value-propositions.htmlt</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The One Who Has The Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/11/the-one-who-has-the-code/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T15:24:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/11/the-one-who-has-the-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Great Experiences]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/designing-great-experiences/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T22:46:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/designing-great-experiences</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surprise amuse delight. Wit and mystery. Stories humanize.  Copy.</p>

<p>Don&#8217;t apply your own prejudices to others. Especially your target audience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Participatory Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/the-participatory-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T22:43:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/the-participatory-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You choose to partake in that which interests you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice Makes Perfect]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/practice-makes-perfect/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T22:40:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/practice-makes-perfect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I find that making interfaces is relaxing for me. I get in the zone. And start riffing.</p>

<p>Years ago I remember asking in an interview about exploration prior to build. I got a blank stare.</p>

<p>And then what happens? Then what? It&#8217;s almost like you&#8217;re creating a script for others to follow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design From The Inside Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/design-from-the-inside-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T21:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/design-from-the-inside-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Point: Ask what is the Core of the page. Then design outwards from there.</p>

<p>Eg. Dashboard (core is calendar)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About me]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/about-me/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T21:25:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/about-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Top interaction designer.  Unicorn.  Unicorns are not loud or obnoxious. They are rare and shy but all-powerful.</p>

<p>The world is clamoring for new experiences (like Disneyland)</p>

<p>Blue oceans.</p>

<p>Creative copywriting. Advertising. Created every single interaction possible known to man using easel. Capsule projects which grow into companies. Marketing and selling before coding. Risk profile and aversion. Using data to drive decisions.  Making money. Making a difference. Making jobs.</p>

<p>Opportunistic artist.  Contrarian.  Swimming in the opposite direction.  Fashion.</p>

<p>Top 5 people in the valley. Who are they? Quality of connections.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m ok, you&#8217;re ok.</p>

<p>What would you like the world to be like. Then create it via this thing called the interface.</p>

<p>omnomn</p>

<p>from play to build</p>

<p>Locbox - a marketing solution for SMBs
Stockfish - redefining stock photography
Mirrror - human-powered people search
Juggler - visual project management tool
Here App - iphone app which provides your location to another
Art - an easy way for one to &#8216;participate&#8217; in art
News - Best way to learn about top stories going on in the world in 5 minutes a day. Flipboard?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's About Respect]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/its-about-respect/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T21:21:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/10/its-about-respect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Design for users. Strip down product. Market fragmentation.</p>

<p>History from features war to the great strip down.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/09/playtime/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T14:57:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/09/playtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>3 month calendar. ooh. a slider thingy-!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking New Ground]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/09/breaking-new-ground/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T10:40:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/09/breaking-new-ground</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just imported BC calendar into easel. Sat staring at it for about 5 min. Like Rover just landed on the moon.</p>

<p>Gun it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Is Too Short For Bad Interfaces]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/02/life-is-too-short-for-bad-interfaces/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T22:26:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/02/life-is-too-short-for-bad-interfaces</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build and Build Fast]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/01/build-and-build-fast/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T22:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/01/build-and-build-fast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time to procure 3 icons: 3 minutes. Previous time to procurement: at least 20 minutes.  Here&#8217;s the breakdown:</p>

<p>I&#8217;d have to remember where I&#8217;d put those vector icon files. Then it would take a few mins to fire up an Adobe product. I think my MacBook Pro was resisting Photoshop. I had several sets, and not knowing which one had the ones I needed, I&#8217;d open all of them. Wait a few more minutes. Then I&#8217;d have to sift through all of them. It was like finding a needle in a haystack. And this was me having icon sets already. Imagine if one didn&#8217;t have them. Tack on another half hour minimum spent online sifting through all the icon sets on the internet, trying to find the best bang for your buck. Makes my hair stand on end just thinking about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
