<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-24T18:50:44-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[omnomn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doing The Startup Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_whimsy/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T20:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kuobot.github.com/omnomn/blog/2012/11/24/P_whimsy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>San Francico is a sort of a microcosm in that people from all over the world flock here to &#8220;do the startup thing&#8221;.  I&#8217;ve met people from Europe, Australia, the Midwest, China and more. This is the place where magic happens. Perhaps if you come here, some of the magic will rub off on you too. It sort of reminds me of Dubai, where there was no such thing as a shortage of land. They simply created it. Here in the Valley, there&#8217;s no shortage of ideas. You simply come up with more.  There&#8217;s no shame in trying and failing. The real shame is in not trying at all.</p>

<p>This is largely what the New Web is all about. Less about what technology can do, than what <i>we</i> can do with technology, which is to prove something of ourselves.</p>

<p>Johann Wolfgang von Goethe (28 August 1749 – 22 March 1832) was a German novelist, dramatist, poet, humanist, scientist, philosopher, and for ten years chief minister of state at Weimar.  He stated most eloquently about the human spirit we witness today:</p>

<p>“Until one is committed, there is hesitancy, the chance to draw back. Concerning all acts of initiative (and creation), there is one elementary truth, the ignorance of which kills countless ideas and splendid plans: that the moment one definitely commits oneself, then Providence moves too. All sorts of things occur to help one that would never otherwise have occurred. A whole stream of events issues from the decision, raising in one&#8217;s favor all manner of unforeseen incidents and meetings and material assistance, which no man could have dreamed would have come his way. Whatever you can do, or dream you can do, begin it. Boldness has genius, power, and magic in it. Begin it now.”</p>

<p>Where in LA you would hear people talking about blue jeans and sporting the latest fashionable large handbags and sunglasses, instead here you hear about the latest idea, what the experience will be like, and plans to gain traction. There is definitely a fashion undercurrent in the air here, and as I was pondering this the other day I listed a dozen of them.  Here they are in no particular order.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Gone: Heavy spec writing.<br>
Instead: Lightweight, standups instead.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The unknown corporation.<br>
Instead: The personable touch.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Ignoring the customer<br>
Instead: The customer is king.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Poor user experiences<br>
Instead: Spotlight on the user experience. Whimsy, personality, fun. Character. This is why copyrighting is so important these days.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Just build it <br>
Instead: Figure out what you will build and market and sell it first. Then build it</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Silos of demarcatation<br>
Instead: Integrated, small design-build teams who can turn on a dime.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Boring jobs<br>
Instead: You can have your cake and eat it too</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: The corporate zombie<br>
Instead: The enlightened, self-motivated employee</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Playing by the rules<br>
Intead: Making the rules. Or in some cases, breaking them first</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Believing you can&#8217;t.<br>
Instead: Believing you can.</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional models and institutions<br>
Instead: Forging your own way</p></li>
<li><p>Gone: Traditional glass ceilings<br>
Instead: Fuck you money</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
